<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Tom Preston-Werner</title>
 <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/"/>
 <updated>2010-04-20T22:49:56-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Tom Preston-Werner</name>
   <email>tom@mojombo.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>How did we get here?</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2010/04/15/thats-how-I-escaped-my-certain-fate.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/2010/04/15/thats-how-I-escaped-my-certain-fate</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;How did we get here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;15 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;APRIL&lt;/span&gt; 2010 by maxwell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;//maxwell rant, go&lt;br /&gt;
The way I see it, people have to solving the wrong problem online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know that the Internet has forever changed the way people communicate online.  And I think most people, including myself, say it has changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these big social network and sharing sites say that they are changing the way people communicate, changing the way they express themselves, and changing the way human beings interact.   But when you really think about it, we are forced to express ourselves through these platforms, rather than these services simply being cursory to how we communicate.  The communication becoming about the platform, not about you and your friends.  This of course, with much reason, is because these services currently would like to make money from your eyeballs being on their website, a topic which I won&amp;#8217;t begin to unpack here. That&amp;#8217;s their &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GOAL&lt;/span&gt; (which is all right.  you shouldn&amp;#8217;t have any disillusions to this point).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But lets talk about communication here for a movement.  Last time I checked, it was between two human beings, mediated through something.  Our voices traveling through the air, as noise waves.  A letter, in written word.  Even a phone call, through telephone wires, a receiver, and a speaker.  Each one of these mediums has it&amp;#8217;s own unique benefits and pitfalls, but ultimately is responsible for connecting two people together.  Each of these media also presents a unique opportunity, structured in a way which the communication it allows for is not possible any other way.  The medium itself attempts to fade into the background, while trying to seem agnostic as possible to the content and communication, so much so that (to paraphrase Marshell McLuhan) the &amp;#8220;medium becomes the message&amp;#8221;.  What you are able to express is a function of the limitations of said media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I checked, Facebook wasn&amp;#8217;t a medium.  The Internet was. Facebook may try really hard to make you think it is one, trying to get you to funnel all of your personal communication through its platform, that somehow it &amp;#8220;Facebook-ness&amp;#8221; your communiqué. This isn&amp;#8217;t the case.  This is technology which is over-developed, and over constrained.  So much of the structure and centralized nature of Facebook and other services is just arbitrary infrastructure which actually &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;INHIBITS&lt;/span&gt; your communication, because the problem Facebook is trying to solve is to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have the technology and the passion to fix this over built solution.  We can solve the right problem.  That problem is making the absolute best way for people to communicate with individuals, groups, and the tubes at large.  This is the beauty of open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;#8217;t that hard to build a system that is truly built to facilitate the kinds of interaction we have come to expect online, in a way which you don&amp;#8217;t have to sacrifice convenience, privacy, or fun.  Facebook makes it easy to share stuff.  There is no reason that a good peace of open source software couldn&amp;#8217;t do the exact same thing, without the oversight, and loss of ownership.  The &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ONLY&lt;/span&gt; goal we really have is to make it fun and easy to communicate with the people you care about.  Who cares about what kinda stuff they want to share with you?  You arn&amp;#8217;t friends with Facebook.  You are friends with people. Facebook is not a person.  They don&amp;#8217;t need to be evolved with every bit of talk you have with your friends.  The fact that they they say they &amp;#8220;need&amp;#8221; to be present is an arbitrary technological limitation.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>